Tonie Victor

Full-Stack Software Developer

(2) 081-517-6503

fin tonie.netlify.app

github.com/tonie-ng

Experience

Software Developer @AMYVIE VENTURES

Nov 2022 - present

- Developed and shipped highly interactive web applications for various clients across the globe.
- Worked closely with the design and management team to architect, develop and implement several features based on client's demands.

Software Developer Intern @HNG9

Oct 2022 - Dec 2022

- Write modern, performant, and robust code for a diverse array of Task and internal projects.
- Communicate and collaborate with multi-disciplinary teams of engineers, designers, and Product Managers on a daily basis.

Front End Developer @NNSONYE

2022 - present

- Collaborated with a small team of student designers, developers and product managers to spearhead the development of the NNSONYE website.
- Developed and maintained code for in-house projects and websites primarily using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and ReactJS.

Project Experience

Crypto-Currency Application

Technology Stack - React, Ant Design Library, Redux Toolkit and some public APIs

- > I built a web application that keeps you updated with the latest news and information about crypto-currencies
- It features a home page, news page, crypto-details page and a crypto currency page. All these were linked using the React-router DOM
- For this project I was able to practicalize working more with ReactJS and Redux. I also learnt and practiced different ways to make API calls:

E-Commerce API

Technology Stack - NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, CryptoJS Hashing Library, Stripe and JWT

- Developed a fully functional API that can be used with an E-commerce web UI, and also an Admin Dashboard.
- It contains several routes and endpoints including: User route, Product route, Stripe route Order route etc.
- It also comes with an Authentication and a verification route (using JWT) that handles user login and verifies user token validation.
- Integrated the stripe payment gateway to allow for card payments after purchase.

Skills

Programming Languages

JavaScript (ES6), Python, HTML, CSS/Sass,

Libraries & Frameworks

React, Node.js, Express, Mongoose, SQLAlchemy, FastAPI

Database

MongoDB, Postgress, Redis

Tools & Platforms

Git, Netlify, Heroku, GitHub, Postman, React Testing Library, Jest, Axios, Google AUTH, Redux Toolkit, ContextAPI, Firebase

Education

University of Port Harcourt

2018 - present // Rivers State, Nigeria Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical/ Electronics Engineering

Profile

My name is Tonie and I create functional web applications.

I've spent the last few years working with multiple technologies across several companies and projects and I'm focused on using my skillset and experience to develop real world digital products for consumers.

I am passionate about using the most effective and efficient approaches to solve problems.

I am a goal driven individual and an excellent team player and I'm excited to make the leap and continue refining my skills with the right company.

Interests

Football and Basketball, Music, Movies, Biking and Analyzing the financial market